Guide to the Western Pennsylvania Buhl Network (WEBNET, Inc.) Records, 1976-1988 AIS.1990.13
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Western Pennsylvania Buhl Network (WEBNET, Inc.) Records
1976-1988
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Western Pennsylvania Buhl Network
AIS.1990.13
2.5 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
WEBNET, Inc. was a library consortium created to develop resource sharing among libraries in the Pittsburgh area. The collection contains by-laws, minutes, correspondence, grants, budgets, reports, contracts, and activity files, 1976-1988.
History
WEBNET was conceived by Allen Kent, Office of Communication Programs, University of Pittsburgh. WEBNET's purpose was to develop resource sharing among libraries in the Pittsburgh area. In 1974 the Buhl Foundation awarded a grant that ran until 1980 to set up both a technical and public services module. In 1980 a second grant from the Buhl Foundation was awarded for the development of a circulation module which was completed in 1983. WEBNET was awarded a third grant in 1983 to further develop their hardware and software as well as a governance structure. WEBNET members included the libraries of California State College (through 1983), Westminster College, Chatham College, Carlow College, Point Park College, University of Pittsburgh Libraries (through 1983), and the School of Library and Information Sciences, University of Pittsburgh. WEBNET was dissolved in 1988.
Scope and Content
The Records of Western Pennsylvania Buhl Network (WEBNET, Inc.), 1976-1988, contains by-laws, minutes, correspondence, grants, budgets, reports, contracts, and activity files, 1976-1988. All items are arranged in alphabetical order.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Deposited by the Pittsburgh Regional Library Center, 1990.
Previous Citation
Western Pennsylvania Buhl Network (WEBNET, Inc.)Records, 1976-1988, AIS.1990.13, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
WEBNET, Inc. (Westrn Pennsylvania Buhl Network), Pittsburgh, Records, 1976-1988, Archives of Industrial Society, University of Pittsburgh Library System, University of Pittsburgh.
Associations; Libraries -- Pennsylvania; Library cooperation -- Pennsylvania; Buhl Foundation; University of Pittsburgh; Western Pennsylvania Buhl Network
- Administrative Contracts, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- Administrative Headquarters, Nebraska Library Commission - RFP, no date (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Articles of Election to Dissolve, no date (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Budget, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Budget, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 6-8)
- Buhl Grant, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Buhl Grant, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Buhl Grant, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Buhl Grant, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Buhl Proposal, no date (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
- Bumped Statistics, no date (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Bylaws, no date (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Circulation Module Report, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Circulation Module Report, no date (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Circulation Module - Designs, no date (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Conference, no date (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Correspondence, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Correspondence, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Correspondence, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Correspondence, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Correspondence, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Correspondence, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Correspondence, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Correspondence, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Correspondence, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Correspondence, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Correspondence, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Data Research Associates (DRA), no date (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Directors Officers Insurance, no date (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Database Structures, no date (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Display Terminal, no date (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Intro. Message, no date (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Functional Specification, no date (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Public Service Version, no date (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Reference Sheet, no date (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Technical Service Version, no date (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Evaluation I II., no date (Box 1, Folder 42-43)
- Evaluation Identification Number, no date (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Federal Identification Number, no date (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Financial Statements, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Incorporation Papers, no date (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Information Systems Consultants, Inc. (ISCI), no date (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Insurance (property), no date (Box 1, Folder 49)
- IRS, no date (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
- Legal, no date (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Library Directors Committee, no date (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
- LSCA III, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Meetings, 1976-1987 (Box 2, Folder 7-18)
- Membership Invoices, no date (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Online Interface, no date (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Progress Reports, no date (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Prospective Members, no date (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Quarterly Administrative Reports, 1985-1987 (Box 2, Folder 23-25)
- Retrospective Conversion, no date (Box 2, Folder 26-27)
- Specifications and Library Auto. Study, no date (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Surveys, no date (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Timetable, no date (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Travel, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Westminster Proposal, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- User's Manual, no date (Box 2, Folder 33)
- User's Manual - Point Park, no date (Box 2, Folder 34)
- User's Manual - Westminster, no date (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Webnet Documentation, April, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Webnet Circulation System, no date (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Webnet Circulation and Online Catalog Manual, no date (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Webnet Chronology, 1985-1988 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Pamphlets Describing Webnet, no date (Box 2, Folder 40)